Vladimir O. Talibov

Last update: September 11, 2022

Småbrukets backe 31

vladimir.o.talibov@gmail.com

SE 141 58, Huddinge, Sweden

Summary

Biochemist with a passion for target-based drug discovery. I like to keep a bridge between physical chemistry and protein science. Experienced in kinetic and biophysical methods.

Skills

 $\underline{Experimental:} \ Biochemical \ assays, \ biophysical \ methods \ (SPR \ biosensors, ITC, TSA), \\ \underline{enzymology, \ protein \ techniques, \ expression\&purification, \ automation, \ protein \ crystallography$

Experience

 $Associate\ Principal\ Scientist,\ Senior\ Scientist$

Mar 2021 - current

Sprint Bioscience AB, Huddinge, Sweden

- Biochemical and biophysical methods in DMTA cycle
- Support of FBLD projects as a member of Protein Science team
- Protein biochemistry.

Researcher

Aug 2019 – Feb 2021

MAX IV Laboratory, Lund, Sweden

- Operation protocols of core fragment screening facility
- Design, curation and maintenance of in-house fragment library
- BioMAX user support as a beamline scientist, including on-call service.

PhD student, Researcher

Apr 2014 – Jun 2019

Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

- Development of biophysical and enzymatic assays for ligand discovery
- Maintenance of biosensors and chromatographic equipment
- Teaching (20%, MSc-level courses).

Laboratory Assistant

Jul 2012 – Feb 2014

OOO "Biochip-IMB", Moscow, Russia

- Validation of multiplex clinical diagnostics assays
- QC of proteins, synthetic oligonucleotides and reactive small molecules.

Education

PhD in Biochemistry

2014 - 2019

Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden Advisor: Prof. U. Helena Danielson

"Interaction kinetic analysis in drug design, enzymology and protein research".

BSc&MSc in Chemistry

2008 - 2013

Moscow State University, Moscow, Russia Specialisation in bioorganic chemistry.

Interests

Molecular recognition, as say technology, early stage drug discovery, mechanistic characterization.

Publications

h-index - 9, research articles - 12; details are available at GScholar.

Other: reviews - 2, book chapters - 1, patents - 1.